{"34687720": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "rory mcilroy will take a one-shot lead into the final round of the wgc-hsbc champions after carding a three-under", "summary_upper": "Rory McIlroy will take a one-shot lead into the final round of the Wgc-Hsbc champions after carding a Three-Under", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 4, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Rory"}, {"start": 5, "end": 12, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "McIlroy"}, {"start": 25, "end": 28, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "one"}, {"start": 63, "end": 75, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the Wgc-Hsbc"}, {"start": 102, "end": 107, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "Three"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "northern ireland's rory mcilroy is one shot off the lead after the first round of the fedex championship in california.", "summary_upper": "Northern Ireland 's Rory McIlroy is one shot off the lead after the first round of the FedEx championship in California .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 19, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Northern Ireland 's"}, {"start": 20, "end": 32, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Rory McIlroy"}, {"start": 36, "end": 39, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "one"}, {"start": 68, "end": 73, "label": 2, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "first"}, {"start": 87, "end": 92, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "FedEx"}, {"start": 109, "end": 119, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "California"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "rory mcilroy moved to within a shot of joint leaders victor dubuisson and jaco van zyl after the third round of the turkish airlines open.", "summary_upper": "Rory McIlroy moved to within a shot of joint leaders Victor Dubuisson and Jaco van Zyl after the third round of the Turkish Airlines open .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 4, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Rory"}, {"start": 5, "end": 12, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "McIlroy"}, {"start": 53, "end": 59, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Victor"}, {"start": 60, "end": 69, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Dubuisson"}, {"start": 74, "end": 78, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Jaco"}, {"start": 79, "end": 82, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "van"}, {"start": 83, "end": 86, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Zyl"}, {"start": 97, "end": 102, "label": -1, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "third"}, {"start": 116, "end": 132, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Turkish Airlines"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "rory mcilroy's french open final with a three-under-par stoppage of 71 to take a one-shot lead into the final round of the dubai championships.", "summary_upper": "Rory McIlroy 's French Open final with a Three-Under-Par stoppage of 71 to take a one-shot lead into the final round of the Dubai championships .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 4, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Rory"}, {"start": 5, "end": 12, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "McIlroy"}, {"start": 13, "end": 15, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "'s"}, {"start": 16, "end": 22, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "French"}, {"start": 69, "end": 71, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "71"}, {"start": 82, "end": 85, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "one"}, {"start": 124, "end": 129, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Dubai"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "world number one rory mcilroy missed the cut at the us pga championship as he took a two-shot lead after two rounds of the honda classic", "summary_upper": "World number one Rory McIlroy missed the cut at the US PGA Championship as he took a two-shot lead after two rounds of the Honda classic", "ents": [{"start": 13, "end": 16, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "one"}, {"start": 17, "end": 29, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Rory McIlroy"}, {"start": 52, "end": 54, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 55, "end": 71, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "PGA Championship"}, {"start": 85, "end": 88, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "two"}, {"start": 105, "end": 108, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "two"}, {"start": 123, "end": 128, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Honda"}]}}, "21267591": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the leader of bahrain's main opposition party has said there needs to be dialogue between the kingdom's crown prince and government.", "summary_upper": "The leader of Bahrain 's main opposition party has said there needs to be dialogue between the kingdom 's crown prince and government .", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 21, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bahrain"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the leader of the saudi prince of saudi arabia has called for a dialogue between the government and the government.", "summary_upper": "The leader of the Saudi prince of Saudi Arabia has called for a dialogue between the government and the government .", "ents": [{"start": 18, "end": 23, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Saudi"}, {"start": 34, "end": 46, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Saudi Arabia"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "the leader of bahrain's main opposition group, al-wefaq, has called for the crown prince to attend talks aimed at ending nearly two years of unrest.", "summary_upper": "The leader of Bahrain 's main opposition group , Al-Wefaq , has called for the crown prince to attend talks aimed at ending nearly two years of unrest .", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 21, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bahrain"}, {"start": 49, "end": 57, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Al-Wefaq"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the leader of bahrain's crown prince, sheikh salman hamad, has said he is ready to go on a demonstration\" .\"", "summary_upper": "The leader of Bahrain 's crown prince , Sheikh Salman Hamad , has said he is ready to go on a demonstration '' . ''", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 21, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bahrain"}, {"start": 47, "end": 53, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Salman"}, {"start": 54, "end": 59, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Hamad"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "bahrain's former king salman has urged the government to help restore the country's monarchy.", "summary_upper": "Bahrain 's former king Salman has urged the government to help restore the country 's monarchy .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bahrain"}, {"start": 23, "end": 29, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Salman"}]}}, "29347895": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "veteran classical music conductor christopher hogwood has died at the age of 83.", "summary_upper": "Veteran classical music conductor Christopher Hogwood has died at the age of 83 .", "ents": [{"start": 34, "end": 45, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Christopher"}, {"start": 46, "end": 53, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Hogwood"}, {"start": 66, "end": 79, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the age of 83"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "tributes have been paid to british composer michael handel, who has died at the age of 89.", "summary_upper": "Tributes have been paid to British composer Michael Handel , who has died at the age of 89 .", "ents": [{"start": 27, "end": 34, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "British"}, {"start": 44, "end": 51, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Michael"}, {"start": 52, "end": 58, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Handel"}, {"start": 77, "end": 90, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the age of 89"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "british conductor christopher hogwood has died aged 73.", "summary_upper": "British conductor Christopher Hogwood has died aged 73 .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "British"}, {"start": 18, "end": 29, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Christopher"}, {"start": 30, "end": 37, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Hogwood"}, {"start": 52, "end": 54, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "73"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "music conductor christopher hogwood has died at the age of 88, his family has said. said he has died at the age of 72.", "summary_upper": "Music conductor Christopher Hogwood has died at the age of 88 , his family has said . said he has died at the age of 72 .", "ents": [{"start": 16, "end": 27, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Christopher"}, {"start": 28, "end": 35, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Hogwood"}, {"start": 48, "end": 61, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the age of 88"}, {"start": 106, "end": 119, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the age of 72"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "tributes have been paid to renowned renowned music director christopher lee, who has died at the age of 86.", "summary_upper": "Tributes have been paid to renowned renowned music director Christopher Lee , who has died at the age of 86 .", "ents": [{"start": 60, "end": 71, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Christopher"}, {"start": 72, "end": 75, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Lee"}, {"start": 94, "end": 107, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the age of 86"}]}}, "37618111": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the number of homicides recorded by police in scotland has fallen to its lowest level since 2009.", "summary_upper": "The number of homicides recorded by police in Scotland has fallen to its lowest level since 2009 .", "ents": [{"start": 46, "end": 54, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}, {"start": 92, "end": 96, "label": 1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "2009"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the number of recorded crimes in scotland has fallen to its lowest level since records began, according to new figures.", "summary_upper": "The number of recorded crimes in Scotland has fallen to its lowest level since records began , according to new figures .", "ents": [{"start": 33, "end": 41, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "the number of murders in scotland has fallen again, according to new figures.", "summary_upper": "The number of murders in Scotland has fallen again , according to new figures .", "ents": [{"start": 25, "end": 33, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the number of recorded homicide in scotland has fallen to its lowest level since records began last year, according to a new report.", "summary_upper": "The number of recorded homicide in Scotland has fallen to its lowest level since records began last year , according to a new report .", "ents": [{"start": 35, "end": 43, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}, {"start": 95, "end": 104, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "last year"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "the number of homicides recorded in scotland last year was at its lowest level since records began, official figures show.", "summary_upper": "The number of homicides recorded in Scotland last year was at its lowest level since records began , official figures show .", "ents": [{"start": 36, "end": 44, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}, {"start": 45, "end": 54, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "last year"}]}}, "37895159": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "bournemouth manager eddie howe says his side are  struggling \" after losing 2-0 to hull on saturday.\"", "summary_upper": "Bournemouth manager Eddie Howe says his side are struggling `` after losing 2-0 to Hull on Saturday . ''", "ents": [{"start": 20, "end": 25, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Eddie"}, {"start": 26, "end": 30, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Howe"}, {"start": 76, "end": 77, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "2"}, {"start": 91, "end": 99, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "Saturday"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "bournemouth boss eddie howe says his side's poor start to the premier league season was a \"disaster\" .", "summary_upper": "Bournemouth boss Eddie Howe says his side 's poor start to the Premier League season was a `` disaster '' .", "ents": [{"start": 17, "end": 22, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Eddie"}, {"start": 23, "end": 27, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Howe"}, {"start": 59, "end": 77, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the Premier League"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "bournemouth boss eddie howe admits his side's sudden lack of confidence in front of goal is \"baffling\" .", "summary_upper": "Bournemouth boss Eddie Howe admits his side 's sudden lack of confidence in front of goal is `` baffling '' .", "ents": [{"start": 17, "end": 22, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Eddie"}, {"start": 23, "end": 27, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Howe"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "bournemouth manager eddie howe has urged his players to avoid a \"lack of confidence\" in the premier league.", "summary_upper": "Bournemouth manager Eddie Howe has urged his players to avoid a `` lack of confidence '' in the Premier League .", "ents": [{"start": 20, "end": 25, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Eddie"}, {"start": 26, "end": 30, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Howe"}, {"start": 92, "end": 110, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the Premier League"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "bournemouth manager eddie howe says his side's  lack of confidence \" in their bid to win a top-six premier league away from premier league relegation\"", "summary_upper": "Bournemouth manager Eddie Howe says his side 's lack of confidence `` in their bid to win a top-six Premier League away from Premier League relegation ''", "ents": [{"start": 20, "end": 25, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Eddie"}, {"start": 26, "end": 30, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Howe"}, {"start": 96, "end": 99, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "six"}, {"start": 100, "end": 114, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Premier League"}, {"start": 125, "end": 139, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Premier League"}]}}, "34148931": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "australia's prime minister tony abbott has said his country has  no regrets \" over the controversial immigration policy.\"", "summary_upper": "Australia 's prime minister Tony Abbott has said his country has no regrets `` over the controversial immigration policy . ''", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 9, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Australia"}, {"start": 28, "end": 32, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tony"}, {"start": 33, "end": 39, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Abbott"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "australian prime minister tony abbott has called for a ban on migrants entering the mediterranean sea.", "summary_upper": "Australian prime minister Tony Abbott has called for a ban on migrants entering the Mediterranean Sea .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 10, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Australian"}, {"start": 26, "end": 30, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tony"}, {"start": 31, "end": 37, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Abbott"}, {"start": 80, "end": 101, "label": 2, "type": "LOC", "ent": "the Mediterranean Sea"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "australian prime minister tony abbott has said the refugee and migrant crisis in europe is proof of the need for tough asylum policies.", "summary_upper": "Australian prime minister Tony Abbott has said the refugee and migrant crisis in Europe is proof of the need for tough asylum policies .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 10, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Australian"}, {"start": 26, "end": 30, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tony"}, {"start": 31, "end": 37, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Abbott"}, {"start": 81, "end": 87, "label": -1, "type": "LOC", "ent": "Europe"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "australia's executive committee has said it is \"inhumane\" and \"ruthlessly effective\" the country's \"genocide\" scandal.", "summary_upper": "Australia 's executive committee has said it is `` inhumane '' and `` ruthlessly effective '' the country 's `` genocide '' scandal .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 9, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Australia"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "australia's prime minister tony abbott has accused the country's media of trying to stop migrants trying to hide their boats.", "summary_upper": "Australia 's prime minister Tony Abbott has accused the country 's media of trying to stop migrants trying to hide their boats .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 9, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Australia"}, {"start": 28, "end": 32, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tony"}, {"start": 33, "end": 39, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Abbott"}]}}, "37546354": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the us says it has suspended talks with russia over a cessation of hostilities in syria.", "summary_upper": "The US says it has suspended talks with Russia over a cessation of hostilities in Syria .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 6, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 40, "end": 46, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 82, "end": 87, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Syria"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the us has accused the us of \"barbarism\" over its bombardment of rebel-held areas in the syrian city of aleppo.", "summary_upper": "The US has accused the US of `` barbarism '' over its bombardment of rebel-held areas in the Syrian city of Aleppo .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 6, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 23, "end": 25, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 93, "end": 99, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Syrian"}, {"start": 108, "end": 114, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Aleppo"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "the us has said it is suspending talks with russia over syria, accusing moscow of having failed to live up\" to its commitments under a ceasefire deal.\"", "summary_upper": "The US has said it is suspending talks with Russia over Syria , accusing Moscow of having failed to live up '' to its commitments under a ceasefire deal . ''", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 6, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 44, "end": 50, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 56, "end": 61, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Syria"}, {"start": 73, "end": 79, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Moscow"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "russia has urged the united nations to help tackle the cessation of hostilities in the syrian city of aleppo.", "summary_upper": "Russia has urged the United Nations to help tackle the cessation of hostilities in the Syrian city of Aleppo .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 6, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 17, "end": 35, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the United Nations"}, {"start": 87, "end": 93, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Syrian"}, {"start": 102, "end": 108, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Aleppo"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "russia has said it will suspend air strikes in syria from the city of aleppo in an effort to halt the us-led truce in syria.", "summary_upper": "Russia has said it will suspend air strikes in Syria from the city of Aleppo in an effort to halt the US-led truce in Syria .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 6, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 47, "end": 52, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Syria"}, {"start": 70, "end": 76, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Aleppo"}, {"start": 102, "end": 104, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 118, "end": 123, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Syria"}]}}, "19311364": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the government should sell off some of the most expensive social housing stock in the uk, the government has said.", "summary_upper": "The government should sell off some of the most expensive social housing stock in the UK , the government has said .", "ents": [{"start": 86, "end": 88, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "former labour leader jeremy corbyn has defended the government's plan to scrap social housing in england.", "summary_upper": "Former Labour leader Jeremy Corbyn has defended the government 's plan to scrap social housing in England .", "ents": [{"start": 7, "end": 13, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Labour"}, {"start": 21, "end": 27, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Jeremy"}, {"start": 28, "end": 34, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Corbyn"}, {"start": 98, "end": 105, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "England"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "councils should consider selling off their most expensive houses to build more cheap homes, the government says.", "summary_upper": "Councils should consider selling off their most expensive houses to build more cheap homes , the government says .", "ents": []}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the housing and housing associations are something they should look at low wages\" ", "summary_upper": "The housing and housing associations are something they should look at low wages ''", "ents": []}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "the right to be built in social housing should be scrapped in a bid to boost the housing market, a think tank has said.", "summary_upper": "The right to be built in social housing should be scrapped in a bid to boost the housing market , a think tank has said .", "ents": []}}, "22299596": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a post-mortem examination has concluded that a man died from measles and measles.", "summary_upper": "A post-mortem examination has concluded that a man died from measles and measles .", "ents": []}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the family of a five-year-old boy who died after suffering serious head injuries have said they are \"devastated\" by the death of his son.", "summary_upper": "The family of a five-year-old boy who died after suffering serious head injuries have said they are `` devastated '' by the death of his son .", "ents": [{"start": 16, "end": 29, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "five-year-old"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "further tests will be carried out on a man who died while suffering from measles after post-mortem examination results were inconclusive.", "summary_upper": "Further tests will be carried out on a man who died while suffering from measles after post-mortem examination results were inconclusive .", "ents": []}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the family of a woman who died after a measles outbreak have said she is no close to his death.", "summary_upper": "The family of a woman who died after a measles outbreak have said she is no close to his death .", "ents": []}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "an inquest into a swansea man's death has opened.", "summary_upper": "An inquest into a Swansea man 's death has opened .", "ents": [{"start": 18, "end": 25, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Swansea"}]}}, "34593064": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a man has been charged with the rape of a teenage boy in cumbria.", "summary_upper": "A man has been charged with the rape of a teenage boy in Cumbria .", "ents": [{"start": 57, "end": 64, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Cumbria"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a man has been charged with the attempted murder of a 14-year-old boy in cumbria.", "summary_upper": "A man has been charged with the attempted murder of a 14-year-old boy in Cumbria .", "ents": [{"start": 73, "end": 80, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Cumbria"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a man from cumbria has been charged in connection with the rape of a boy 14 years ago.", "summary_upper": "A man from Cumbria has been charged in connection with the rape of a boy 14 years ago .", "ents": [{"start": 11, "end": 18, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Cumbria"}, {"start": 73, "end": 85, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "14 years ago"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a man has been charged with the murder of a man in a suspected sex attack on a father-of-two in cumbria.", "summary_upper": "A man has been charged with the murder of a man in a suspected sex attack on a Father-Of-Two in Cumbria .", "ents": [{"start": 96, "end": 103, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Cumbria"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a man has been charged with raping a 15-year-old boy in cumbria.", "summary_upper": "A man has been charged with raping a 15-year-old boy in Cumbria .", "ents": [{"start": 56, "end": 63, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Cumbria"}]}}, "39263182": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "gateshead remain unbeaten in the national league after being held to a draw by guiseley.", "summary_upper": "Gateshead remain unbeaten in the National League after being held to a draw by Guiseley .", "ents": [{"start": 29, "end": 48, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the National League"}, {"start": 79, "end": 87, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Guiseley"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "guiseley's winless start to the national league season continued with a draw at gateshead.", "summary_upper": "Guiseley 's winless start to the National League season continued with a draw at Gateshead .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 8, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Guiseley"}, {"start": 29, "end": 48, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the National League"}, {"start": 81, "end": 90, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Gateshead"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "gateshead and guiseley extended their unbeaten runs with a 1-1 draw at the gateshead international stadium.", "summary_upper": "Gateshead and Guiseley extended their unbeaten runs with a 1-1 draw at the Gateshead international stadium .", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 22, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Guiseley"}, {"start": 59, "end": 60, "label": -1, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "1"}, {"start": 75, "end": 84, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Gateshead"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "guiseley remain winless at the top of the national league after they were held to a draw at gateshead.", "summary_upper": "Guiseley remain winless at the top of the National League after they were held to a draw at Gateshead .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 8, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Guiseley"}, {"start": 38, "end": 57, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the National League"}, {"start": 92, "end": 101, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Gateshead"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "guiseley continued their 100% start to the national league season with a victory at guiseley.", "summary_upper": "Guiseley continued their 100 % start to the National League season with a victory at Guiseley .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 8, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Guiseley"}, {"start": 25, "end": 30, "label": 0, "type": "PERCENT", "ent": "100 %"}, {"start": 40, "end": 59, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the National League"}, {"start": 85, "end": 93, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Guiseley"}]}}, "25840979": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "plans for a new stadium for bristol city have been given the go-ahead by the city council.", "summary_upper": "Plans for a new stadium for Bristol city have been given the go-ahead by the city council .", "ents": [{"start": 28, "end": 40, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bristol city"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "plans to build a new stadium in bristol have been approved by the club's owner steve lansdown.", "summary_upper": "Plans to build a new stadium in Bristol have been approved by the club 's owner Steve Lansdown .", "ents": [{"start": 32, "end": 39, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Bristol"}, {"start": 80, "end": 85, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Steve"}, {"start": 86, "end": 94, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Lansdown"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a # 40m revamp of bristol city's ashton gate ground will go ahead this summer, the club has announced.", "summary_upper": "A # 40m revamp of Bristol city 's Ashton gate ground will go ahead this summer , the club has announced .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 6, "label": -1, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "40"}, {"start": 18, "end": 33, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bristol city 's"}, {"start": 34, "end": 40, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ashton"}, {"start": 67, "end": 78, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "this summer"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "bristol's mayor has announced it will sign a # [UNK] m upgrade to a new stadium stadium in bristol.", "summary_upper": "Bristol 's mayor has announced it will sign a # [ UNK ] M upgrade to a new stadium stadium in Bristol .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Bristol"}, {"start": 46, "end": 49, "label": 0, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "# ["}, {"start": 50, "end": 53, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UNK"}, {"start": 94, "end": 101, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bristol"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "plans to redevelop bristol city football club's new stadium have been approved.", "summary_upper": "Plans to redevelop Bristol city football club 's new stadium have been approved .", "ents": [{"start": 19, "end": 26, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Bristol"}]}}, "13599161": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "shale gas drilling in lancashire has been suspended after a magnitude-7. 5 earthquake struck.", "summary_upper": "Shale gas drilling in Lancashire has been suspended after a Magnitude-7 . 5 earthquake struck .", "ents": [{"start": 22, "end": 32, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Lancashire"}, {"start": 74, "end": 75, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "5"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the uk's oil and gas authority (nda) has confirmed it is investigating the discovery of a massive earthquake in the uk.", "summary_upper": "The UK 's oil and gas authority ( NDA ) has confirmed it is investigating the discovery of a massive earthquake in the UK .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 6, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}, {"start": 34, "end": 37, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "NDA"}, {"start": 119, "end": 121, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "shale gas test drilling in lancashire has been suspended following an earthquake on the fylde coast.", "summary_upper": "Shale gas test drilling in Lancashire has been suspended following an earthquake on the Fylde coast .", "ents": [{"start": 27, "end": 37, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Lancashire"}, {"start": 88, "end": 93, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Fylde"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "fracking drilling has been confirmed in lancashire, the british geological survey (bgs) has said, following a major quake in april.", "summary_upper": "Fracking drilling has been confirmed in Lancashire , the British Geological Survey ( BGS ) has said , following a major quake in April .", "ents": [{"start": 40, "end": 50, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Lancashire"}, {"start": 53, "end": 82, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the British Geological Survey"}, {"start": 85, "end": 88, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "BGS"}, {"start": 129, "end": 134, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "April"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a fracking operation in lancashire has been suspended after a gas leak was found at the site.", "summary_upper": "A fracking operation in Lancashire has been suspended after a gas leak was found at the site .", "ents": [{"start": 24, "end": 34, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Lancashire"}]}}, "38333121": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a football busker has been found guilty of defrauding the victims of the hillsborough disaster.", "summary_upper": "A football busker has been found guilty of defrauding the victims of the Hillsborough disaster .", "ents": [{"start": 73, "end": 85, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Hillsborough"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a former liverpool police officer has been found guilty of fraud and perverting the course of justice.", "summary_upper": "A former Liverpool police officer has been found guilty of fraud and perverting the course of justice .", "ents": [{"start": 9, "end": 18, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Liverpool"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a bagpipe-playing busker has been convicted of duping people in liverpool into thinking he was collecting for a hillsborough charity.", "summary_upper": "A Bagpipe-Playing busker has been convicted of duping people in Liverpool into thinking he was collecting for a Hillsborough charity .", "ents": [{"start": 2, "end": 17, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Bagpipe-Playing"}, {"start": 64, "end": 73, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Liverpool"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a man has been found guilty of fraud after he was found guilty of fraud at the hillsborough inquests.", "summary_upper": "A man has been found guilty of fraud after he was found guilty of fraud at the Hillsborough Inquests .", "ents": [{"start": 75, "end": 100, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the Hillsborough Inquests"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a man has been found guilty of defrauding an elderly hillsborough charity worker out of thousands of pounds.", "summary_upper": "A man has been found guilty of defrauding an elderly Hillsborough charity worker out of thousands of pounds .", "ents": [{"start": 88, "end": 107, "label": 2, "type": "QUANTITY", "ent": "thousands of pounds"}]}}, "38034979": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "ipswich town ended qpr's seven-game winning run in the championship with a comfortable win at carrow road.", "summary_upper": "Ipswich town ended Qpr 's seven-game winning run in the championship with a comfortable win at Carrow road .", "ents": [{"start": 26, "end": 31, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "seven"}, {"start": 95, "end": 101, "label": 2, "type": "FAC", "ent": "Carrow"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "ipswich town moved up to third in the championship with victory at ipswich town.", "summary_upper": "Ipswich town moved up to third in the championship with victory at Ipswich town .", "ents": [{"start": 25, "end": 30, "label": 2, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "third"}, {"start": 67, "end": 74, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ipswich"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "ipswich town put their scoring problems behind them with their biggest win of the season to sink qpr at portman road.", "summary_upper": "Ipswich town put their scoring problems behind them with their biggest win of the season to sink Qpr at Portman road .", "ents": [{"start": 78, "end": 88, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the season"}, {"start": 104, "end": 111, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Portman"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "jonathan skuse's first-half goal earned ipswich town a draw against qpr in the championship play-off round on aggregate.", "summary_upper": "Jonathan Skuse 's First-half goal earned Ipswich town a draw against Qpr in the championship play-off round on aggregate .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 8, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Jonathan"}, {"start": 9, "end": 14, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Skuse"}, {"start": 15, "end": 17, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "'s"}, {"start": 18, "end": 28, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "First-half"}, {"start": 41, "end": 48, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Ipswich"}, {"start": 69, "end": 72, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Qpr"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "ipswich made it three championship wins from two with a comfortable win over qpr.", "summary_upper": "Ipswich made it three championship wins from two with a comfortable win over Qpr .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Ipswich"}, {"start": 16, "end": 21, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "three"}, {"start": 45, "end": 48, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "two"}, {"start": 77, "end": 80, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "Qpr"}]}}, "36329854": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "worcestershire all-rounder wells wells has signed a new two-year contract with the club.", "summary_upper": "Worcestershire all-rounder wells wells has signed a new two-year contract with the club .", "ents": [{"start": 56, "end": 64, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "two-year"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "nottinghamshire all-rounder jim wells has signed a new two-year contract with the national league club.", "summary_upper": "Nottinghamshire all-rounder Jim wells has signed a new two-year contract with the National League club .", "ents": [{"start": 28, "end": 31, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Jim"}, {"start": 55, "end": 63, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "two-year"}, {"start": 82, "end": 97, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "National League"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "all-rounder tom wells has signed a new two-year contract which will keep him at leicestershire until the end of the 2018 season.", "summary_upper": "All-Rounder Tom wells has signed a new two-year contract which will keep him at Leicestershire until the end of the 2018 season .", "ents": [{"start": 12, "end": 15, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tom"}, {"start": 39, "end": 47, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "two-year"}, {"start": 80, "end": 94, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Leicestershire"}, {"start": 101, "end": 127, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the end of the 2018 season"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "derbyshire international batsman adam wells has signed a new contract with the national league club. show at the end of the 2017 t20 blast.", "summary_upper": "Derbyshire international batsman Adam wells has signed a new contract with the National League club . show at the end of the 2017 T20 blast .", "ents": [{"start": 33, "end": 37, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Adam"}, {"start": 79, "end": 94, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "National League"}, {"start": 110, "end": 129, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the end of the 2017"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "england all-rounder jim wells has signed a new three-year contract extension with the county championship division two champions.", "summary_upper": "England all-rounder Jim wells has signed a new three-year contract extension with the county championship division two champions .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "England"}, {"start": 20, "end": 23, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Jim"}, {"start": 47, "end": 57, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "three-year"}, {"start": 115, "end": 118, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "two"}]}}, "38595401": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "truro city head coach marek churcher has praised his side's performance in the first half of their national rugby league campaign.", "summary_upper": "Truro city head coach Marek Churcher has praised his side 's performance in the first half of their national rugby league campaign .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Truro"}, {"start": 22, "end": 27, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Marek"}, {"start": 28, "end": 36, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Churcher"}, {"start": 76, "end": 90, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the first half"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "redruth head coach marek churcher says his side are capable of reaching the top of the table with a 2-0 win at home to plymouth.", "summary_upper": "Redruth head coach Marek Churcher says his side are capable of reaching the top of the table with a 2-0 win at home to Plymouth .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Redruth"}, {"start": 19, "end": 24, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Marek"}, {"start": 25, "end": 33, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Churcher"}, {"start": 100, "end": 101, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "2"}, {"start": 119, "end": 127, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Plymouth"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "redruth boss marek churcher says his side's front row have been key to the club's good form.", "summary_upper": "Redruth boss Marek Churcher says his side 's front row have been key to the club 's good form .", "ents": [{"start": 13, "end": 18, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Marek"}, {"start": 19, "end": 27, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Churcher"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "exeter city manager brian churcher says his side are \"making 70-plus tackles\" in the premier league title race.", "summary_upper": "Exeter city manager Brian Churcher says his side are `` making 70-plus tackles '' in the Premier league title race .", "ents": [{"start": 20, "end": 25, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Brian"}, {"start": 26, "end": 34, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Churcher"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "reds head coach tom church says the team are in  high tackles \" as they prepare to face cornwall in the one-day cup.\"", "summary_upper": "Reds head coach Tom church says the team are in high tackles `` as they prepare to face Cornwall in the one-day cup . ''", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 4, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Reds"}, {"start": 16, "end": 19, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tom"}, {"start": 88, "end": 96, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Cornwall"}, {"start": 104, "end": 111, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "one-day"}]}}, "33183140": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "indian police have arrested a man in connection with the rape of a nun in the eastern city of kolkata ( calcutta ) in march.", "summary_upper": "Indian police have arrested a man in connection with the rape of a nun in the eastern city of Kolkata ( Calcutta ) in March .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 6, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Indian"}, {"start": 94, "end": 101, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Kolkata"}, {"start": 118, "end": 123, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "March"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a man has been arrested in connection with the rape and murder of a man in the northern indian state of uttar pradesh.", "summary_upper": "A man has been arrested in connection with the rape and murder of a man in the northern Indian state of Uttar Pradesh .", "ents": [{"start": 88, "end": 94, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Indian"}, {"start": 104, "end": 117, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Uttar Pradesh"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "police investigating the rape of an elderly nun in the indian state of west bengal say they have arrested a key suspect in the crime.", "summary_upper": "Police investigating the rape of an elderly nun in the Indian state of West Bengal say they have arrested a key suspect in the crime .", "ents": [{"start": 55, "end": 61, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Indian"}, {"start": 71, "end": 82, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "West Bengal"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a man has been arrested in connection with a gang rape in a convent in kolkata (calcutta), police have said.", "summary_upper": "A man has been arrested in connection with a gang rape in a convent in Kolkata ( Calcutta ) , police have said .", "ents": [{"start": 71, "end": 78, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Kolkata"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "police in the indian city of kolkata ( calcutta ) have charged a man with raping a nun in their home town of kolkata ( calcutta ).", "summary_upper": "Police in the Indian city of Kolkata ( Calcutta ) have charged a man with raping a nun in their home town of Kolkata ( Calcutta ) .", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 20, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Indian"}, {"start": 29, "end": 36, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Kolkata"}, {"start": 109, "end": 116, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Kolkata"}]}}, "32539063": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the bbc has released a series of information about the uk's food market and how they have changed since the start of the decade.", "summary_upper": "The BBC has released a series of information about the UK 's food market and how they have changed since the start of the decade .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 7, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "BBC"}, {"start": 55, "end": 57, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}, {"start": 105, "end": 128, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the start of the decade"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "we've been using your questions to tell us what you want to know about the west midlands.", "summary_upper": "We 've been using your questions to tell us what you want to know about the West Midlands .", "ents": []}, "Gold": {"summary": "advancing technology and manufacturing techniques are among the ingredients of our changing consumer tastes.", "summary_upper": "Advancing technology and manufacturing techniques are among the ingredients of our changing consumer tastes .", "ents": []}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the world's biggest food video may not be able to buy a domestic food freezer, according to a video released by the bbc.", "summary_upper": "The world 's biggest food video may not be able to buy a domestic food freezer , according to a video released by the BBC .", "ents": [{"start": 118, "end": 121, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "BBC"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "we all know what we know about the world of food and technology.", "summary_upper": "We all know what we know about the world of food and technology .", "ents": []}}, "37471830": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "two people in south west scotland have been targeted by telephone scams.", "summary_upper": "Two people in South West Scotland have been targeted by telephone scams .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 3, "label": 1, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "Two"}, {"start": 14, "end": 24, "label": 1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "South West"}, {"start": 25, "end": 33, "label": 1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a man from stranraer has been conned out of the internet by a stranger who stole more than # 1m.", "summary_upper": "A man from Stranraer has been conned out of the Internet by a stranger who stole more than # 1M .", "ents": [{"start": 11, "end": 20, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Stranraer"}, {"start": 81, "end": 95, "label": 2, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "more than # 1M"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a 60-year-old woman in dumfries and galloway has been conned out of # 30,000 just a week after a similar scam netted # 10,000.", "summary_upper": "A 60-year-old woman in Dumfries and Galloway has been conned out of # 30,000 just a week after a similar scam netted # 10,000 .", "ents": [{"start": 23, "end": 31, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Dumfries"}, {"start": 36, "end": 44, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Galloway"}, {"start": 70, "end": 76, "label": -1, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "30,000"}, {"start": 77, "end": 88, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "just a week"}, {"start": 119, "end": 125, "label": -1, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "10,000"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a woman has been conned out of a computer treatment after being rescued from a computer fault in stranraer.", "summary_upper": "A woman has been conned out of a computer treatment after being rescued from a computer fault in Stranraer .", "ents": [{"start": 97, "end": 106, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Stranraer"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a british woman has claimed £70, 000 of cash from a phone scam in stranraer.", "summary_upper": "A British woman has claimed £70 , 000 of cash from a phone scam in Stranraer .", "ents": [{"start": 2, "end": 9, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "British"}, {"start": 29, "end": 31, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "70"}, {"start": 34, "end": 37, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "000"}, {"start": 67, "end": 76, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Stranraer"}]}}, "40642906": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "castleford tigers have appointed former scotland international kevin duffy as their new head coach.", "summary_upper": "Castleford Tigers have appointed former Scotland international Kevin Duffy as their new head coach .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 17, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Castleford Tigers"}, {"start": 40, "end": 48, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}, {"start": 63, "end": 68, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Kevin"}, {"start": 69, "end": 74, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Duffy"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "leigh centurions have appointed former scotland international jamie duffy as their new head coach on a two-year deal.", "summary_upper": "Leigh centurions have appointed former Scotland international Jamie Duffy as their new head coach on a two-year deal .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Leigh"}, {"start": 39, "end": 47, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}, {"start": 62, "end": 67, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Jamie"}, {"start": 68, "end": 73, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Duffy"}, {"start": 103, "end": 111, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "two-year"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "featherstone rovers have appointed john duffy as head coach following the departure of jon sharp.", "summary_upper": "Featherstone rovers have appointed John Duffy as head coach following the departure of Jon sharp .", "ents": [{"start": 35, "end": 39, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "John"}, {"start": 40, "end": 45, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Duffy"}, {"start": 87, "end": 90, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Jon"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "featherstone head coach lee duffy has been ruled out of the rest of the super league season with a shoulder injury.", "summary_upper": "Featherstone head coach Lee Duffy has been ruled out of the rest of the Super league season with a shoulder injury .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 12, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Featherstone"}, {"start": 24, "end": 27, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Lee"}, {"start": 28, "end": 33, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Duffy"}, {"start": 72, "end": 77, "label": 0, "type": "FAC", "ent": "Super"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "leigh centurions have appointed former scotland international matt duffy as their new head coach.", "summary_upper": "Leigh centurions have appointed former Scotland international Matt Duffy as their new head coach .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Leigh"}, {"start": 39, "end": 47, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}, {"start": 62, "end": 66, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Matt"}, {"start": 67, "end": 72, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Duffy"}]}}, "38630833": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a motorcyclist has been airlifted to hospital after falling on a beach in rhondda cynon taff.", "summary_upper": "A motorcyclist has been airlifted to hospital after falling on a beach in Rhondda Cynon Taff .", "ents": [{"start": 74, "end": 92, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Rhondda Cynon Taff"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a man has been airlifted to hospital after falling from a beach in the vale of glamorgan.", "summary_upper": "A man has been airlifted to hospital after falling from a beach in the vale of Glamorgan .", "ents": [{"start": 79, "end": 88, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Glamorgan"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a woman has been airlifted to hospital after falling from a horse on a bridgend county beach.", "summary_upper": "A woman has been airlifted to hospital after falling from a horse on a Bridgend county beach .", "ents": [{"start": 71, "end": 86, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Bridgend county"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a climber has been airlifted to hospital after being rescued from the sea off the coast of bridgend. been named.", "summary_upper": "A climber has been airlifted to hospital after being rescued from the sea off the coast of Bridgend . been named .", "ents": []}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a motorcyclist had to be airlifted to hospital after falling on rocks at a beach on anglesey.", "summary_upper": "A motorcyclist had to be airlifted to hospital after falling on rocks at a beach on Anglesey .", "ents": [{"start": 84, "end": 92, "label": 1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Anglesey"}]}}, "34793274": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the world's first satellite to track flight data from the missing malaysia airlines flight mh370 has been given the go-ahead.", "summary_upper": "The world 's first satellite to track flight data from the missing Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 has been given the go-ahead .", "ents": [{"start": 67, "end": 84, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Malaysia Airlines"}, {"start": 92, "end": 97, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "MH370"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the united nations has announced a new flight to flight flight mh370.", "summary_upper": "The United Nations has announced a new flight to flight flight MH370 .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 18, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "The United Nations"}, {"start": 63, "end": 68, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "MH370"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a deal has been struck on using satellites to track planes, motivated by the disappearance of malaysia airlines flight mh370 last year.", "summary_upper": "A deal has been struck on using satellites to track planes , motivated by the disappearance of Malaysia Airlines flight MH370 last year .", "ents": [{"start": 95, "end": 112, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Malaysia Airlines"}, {"start": 120, "end": 125, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "MH370"}, {"start": 126, "end": 135, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "last year"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the world's largest plane is to be tracking tracking of planes at a world radiocommunication conference in malaysia.", "summary_upper": "The world 's largest plane is to be tracking tracking of planes at a world Radiocommunication conference in Malaysia .", "ents": [{"start": 108, "end": 116, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Malaysia"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "malaysia's aviation authority has decided not to broadcast a satellite tracking system for flight mh370, which was revealed in 2015.", "summary_upper": "Malaysia 's aviation authority has decided not to broadcast a satellite tracking system for flight MH370 , which was revealed in 2015 .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 8, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Malaysia"}, {"start": 99, "end": 104, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "MH370"}, {"start": 129, "end": 133, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "2015"}]}}, "34737471": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the father of a three-year-old boy who went missing in the us has been arrested over his disappearance, according to the fbi.", "summary_upper": "The father of a three-year-old boy who went missing in the US has been arrested over his disappearance , according to the FBI .", "ents": [{"start": 16, "end": 30, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "three-year-old"}, {"start": 59, "end": 61, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 122, "end": 125, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "FBI"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the father of a 12-year-old boy who went missing in ohio has been arrested in ohio, authorities say.", "summary_upper": "The father of a 12-year-old boy who went missing in Ohio has been arrested in Ohio , authorities say .", "ents": [{"start": 52, "end": 56, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ohio"}, {"start": 78, "end": 82, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ohio"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a child missing in alabama since 2002 has been found safe in ohio with his father, who has been charged with abduction, authorities have said.", "summary_upper": "A child missing in Alabama since 2002 has been found safe in Ohio with his father , who has been charged with abduction , authorities have said .", "ents": [{"start": 19, "end": 26, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Alabama"}, {"start": 33, "end": 37, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "2002"}, {"start": 61, "end": 65, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ohio"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the father of a 16-year-old boy who went missing in the us city of ohio has been arrested, the fbi has said.", "summary_upper": "The father of a 16-year-old boy who went missing in the US city of Ohio has been arrested , the FBI has said .", "ents": [{"start": 56, "end": 58, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 67, "end": 71, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ohio"}, {"start": 96, "end": 99, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "FBI"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a 14-year-old boy who went missing in the us state of ohio has been arrested on suspicion of murdering his father, police say.", "summary_upper": "A 14-year-old boy who went missing in the US state of Ohio has been arrested on suspicion of murdering his father , police say .", "ents": [{"start": 42, "end": 44, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "US"}, {"start": 54, "end": 58, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ohio"}]}}, "28328378": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the owners of a recycling plant destroyed by fire in greater manchester have been stripped of their environmental permit.", "summary_upper": "The owners of a recycling plant destroyed by fire in greater Manchester have been stripped of their environmental permit .", "ents": [{"start": 61, "end": 71, "label": 1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Manchester"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "an investigation has been launched into the cause of a fire at a recycling site in greater manchester.", "summary_upper": "An investigation has been launched into the cause of a fire at a recycling site in greater Manchester .", "ents": [{"start": 91, "end": 101, "label": 1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Manchester"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a company which runs a paper recycling plant in salford where a major fire broke out has had its environmental permit revoked.", "summary_upper": "A company which runs a paper recycling plant in Salford where a major fire broke out has had its environmental permit revoked .", "ents": [{"start": 48, "end": 55, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Salford"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a fire at a waste processing plant in greater manchester has been suspended after a fire broke out at the site.", "summary_upper": "A fire at a waste processing plant in greater Manchester has been suspended after a fire broke out at the site .", "ents": [{"start": 46, "end": 56, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Manchester"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a fire that destroyed a disused waste site in eamonn, county down, is to be investigated by the environment agency.", "summary_upper": "A fire that destroyed a disused waste site in Eamonn , county down , is to be investigated by the environment agency .", "ents": [{"start": 46, "end": 52, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Eamonn"}]}}, "26381454": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "russia's lower house of parliament has approved a bill that would allow russia to issue new passports to its citizens.", "summary_upper": "Russia 's lower house of parliament has approved a bill that would allow Russia to issue new passports to its citizens .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 6, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 73, "end": 79, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "russia's new president has called for a new law to allow russian citizens to be barred from leaving the country.", "summary_upper": "Russia 's new president has called for a new law to allow Russian citizens to be barred from leaving the country .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 6, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 58, "end": 65, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "russian mps have proposed new laws that would make it easier for russia to incorporate parts of ukraine, and allow russian citizenship to be fast-tracked.", "summary_upper": "Russian MPs have proposed new laws that would make it easier for Russia to incorporate parts of Ukraine , and allow Russian citizenship to be fast-tracked .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 65, "end": 71, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 96, "end": 103, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ukraine"}, {"start": 116, "end": 123, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "ukraine's president vladimir separatists and russian president vladimir separatists have called on russia to trigger a state tax opportunity for the first time.", "summary_upper": "Ukraine 's president Vladimir separatists and Russian President Vladimir separatists have called on Russia to trigger a state tax opportunity for the first time .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ukraine"}, {"start": 21, "end": 29, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Vladimir"}, {"start": 46, "end": 53, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 64, "end": 72, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Vladimir"}, {"start": 100, "end": 106, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 150, "end": 155, "label": 2, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "first"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "members of the russian parliament are due to call for a referendum on russia's future in crimea.", "summary_upper": "Members of the Russian parliament are due to call for a referendum on Russia 's future in Crimea .", "ents": [{"start": 15, "end": 22, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 70, "end": 76, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 90, "end": 96, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Crimea"}]}}, "36404868": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "mclaren have a lot to do with them this year.", "summary_upper": "Mclaren have a lot to do with them this year .", "ents": [{"start": 35, "end": 44, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "this year"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "formula 1 is one of the world's most powerful formula 1 teams.", "summary_upper": "Formula 1 is one of the world 's most powerful formula 1 teams .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Formula"}, {"start": 8, "end": 9, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "1"}, {"start": 13, "end": 16, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "one"}, {"start": 55, "end": 56, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "1"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "mclaren arrived at this weekend's monaco grand prix, on which they mark the 50th anniversary of their first entry in formula 1, hoping the race would be their best chance of a decent result so far this year-and possibly all season.", "summary_upper": "Mclaren arrived at this weekend 's Monaco grand prix , on which they mark the 50th anniversary of their first entry in Formula 1 , hoping the race would be their best chance of a decent result so far this Year-And possibly all season .", "ents": [{"start": 24, "end": 31, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "weekend"}, {"start": 35, "end": 41, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Monaco"}, {"start": 78, "end": 82, "label": -1, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "50th"}, {"start": 104, "end": 109, "label": -1, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "first"}, {"start": 119, "end": 128, "label": -1, "type": "FAC", "ent": "Formula 1"}, {"start": 205, "end": 213, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "Year-And"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "so much hype, the world's biggest drivers in formula 1, and it is n't only one of the most famous partnerships in the world.", "summary_upper": "So much hype , the world 's biggest drivers in Formula 1 , and it is n't only one of the most famous partnerships in the world .", "ents": [{"start": 47, "end": 56, "label": -1, "type": "FAC", "ent": "Formula 1"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "mclaren's sebastian vettel and kimi raikkonen are in the race for the formula 1 title this weekend.", "summary_upper": "Mclaren 's Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Raikkonen are in the race for the formula 1 title this weekend .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 7, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Mclaren"}, {"start": 11, "end": 27, "label": 2, "type": "LOC", "ent": "Sebastian Vettel"}, {"start": 32, "end": 36, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Kimi"}, {"start": 37, "end": 46, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Raikkonen"}, {"start": 79, "end": 80, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "1"}, {"start": 87, "end": 99, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "this weekend"}]}}, "39860898": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "three men have been arrested on suspicion of murdering a man who was shot dead outside a meat market.", "summary_upper": "Three men have been arrested on suspicion of murdering a man who was shot dead outside a meat market .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": 0, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "Three"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "two men have been arrested on suspicion of murder after a man was shot dead in liverpool.", "summary_upper": "Two men have been arrested on suspicion of murder after a man was shot dead in Liverpool .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 3, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "Two"}, {"start": 79, "end": 88, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Liverpool"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "three men have been arrested on suspicion of murder over the shooting of a man at a meat market.", "summary_upper": "Three men have been arrested on suspicion of murder over the shooting of a man at a meat market .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": -1, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "Three"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a man has been arrested on suspicion of attempted murder after a shooting at a meat market in liverpool.", "summary_upper": "A man has been arrested on suspicion of attempted murder after a shooting at a meat market in Liverpool .", "ents": [{"start": 94, "end": 103, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Liverpool"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a man has been arrested on suspicion of murder after a man was shot dead in liverpool.", "summary_upper": "A man has been arrested on suspicion of murder after a man was shot dead in Liverpool .", "ents": [{"start": 76, "end": 85, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Liverpool"}]}}, "35074007": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "it's one of the most common stories of the festive season.", "summary_upper": "It 's one of the most common stories of the festive season .", "ents": [{"start": 6, "end": 9, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "one"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "it's been a busy year for many of the world's most famous characters.", "summary_upper": "It 's been a busy year for many of the world 's most famous characters .", "ents": [{"start": 11, "end": 22, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "a busy year"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "nothing says christmas more than watching that harry potter movie you've already seen 2,900 times, eating a mountain of lukewarm turkey and trying to work out where you're going to put all those new socks.", "summary_upper": "Nothing says Christmas more than watching that Harry Potter movie you 've already seen 2,900 times , eating a mountain of lukewarm Turkey and trying to work out where you 're going to put all those new socks .", "ents": [{"start": 13, "end": 22, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "Christmas"}, {"start": 47, "end": 52, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Harry"}, {"start": 53, "end": 59, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Potter"}, {"start": 87, "end": 92, "label": -1, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "2,900"}, {"start": 131, "end": 137, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Turkey"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "if you're going to church online, you might have heard of the star wars: the force awakens.", "summary_upper": "If you 're going to church online , you might have heard of the Star Wars : the force Awakens .", "ents": [{"start": 86, "end": 93, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Awakens"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "there's a lot of talk in the church of england and the church of england's christmas sermon.", "summary_upper": "There 's a lot of talk in the church of England and the church of England 's Christmas sermon .", "ents": [{"start": 40, "end": 47, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "England"}, {"start": 66, "end": 73, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "England"}, {"start": 77, "end": 86, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "Christmas"}]}}, "31821135": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a public inquiry into plans to build a circuit of wales racing track in blaenau gwent has opened.", "summary_upper": "A public inquiry into plans to build a circuit of Wales racing track in Blaenau Gwent has opened .", "ents": [{"start": 50, "end": 55, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Wales"}, {"start": 72, "end": 85, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Blaenau Gwent"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "plans for a # 325m motor racing track in blaenau gwent have been given the go-ahead.", "summary_upper": "Plans for a # 325m motor racing track in Blaenau Gwent have been given the go-ahead .", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 17, "label": 1, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "325"}, {"start": 41, "end": 54, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Blaenau Gwent"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a public inquiry into plans to build a # 325m motor racing circuit in the south wales valleys has started.", "summary_upper": "A public inquiry into plans to build a # 325m motor racing circuit in the South Wales valleys has started .", "ents": [{"start": 41, "end": 44, "label": -1, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "325"}, {"start": 74, "end": 85, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "South Wales"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "plans to build a # 120m waste processing circuit in monmouthshire have been approved by the government's plans to take over.", "summary_upper": "Plans to build a # 120M waste processing circuit in Monmouthshire have been approved by the government 's plans to take over .", "ents": [{"start": 19, "end": 22, "label": 2, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "120"}, {"start": 52, "end": 65, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Monmouthshire"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a public inquiry into the future of land at blaenau gwent's blaenau gwent plant has heard the plan will not", "summary_upper": "A public inquiry into the future of land at Blaenau Gwent 's Blaenau Gwent plant has heard the plan will not", "ents": [{"start": 44, "end": 60, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Blaenau Gwent 's"}, {"start": 61, "end": 74, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Blaenau Gwent"}]}}, "39600124": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a newspaper in the russian republic of chechnya has passed a resolution to condemn the publication of a report by chechnya's state news agency", "summary_upper": "A newspaper in the Russian republic of Chechnya has passed a resolution to condemn the publication of a report by Chechnya 's state news agency", "ents": [{"start": 19, "end": 26, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 39, "end": 47, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Chechnya"}, {"start": 114, "end": 122, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Chechnya"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a report by a russian newspaper has called on the russian government to apologise for a ban on gay people in the republic of chechnya.", "summary_upper": "A report by a Russian newspaper has called on the Russian government to apologise for a ban on gay people in the republic of Chechnya .", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 21, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 50, "end": 57, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 125, "end": 133, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Chechnya"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "the russian daily novaya gazeta says it is alarmed by a chechen muslim call for \"retribution\" after the paper reported violence against gay men in chechnya.", "summary_upper": "The Russian daily Novaya Gazeta says it is alarmed by a Chechen Muslim call for `` retribution '' after the paper reported violence against gay men in Chechnya .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 11, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 18, "end": 24, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Novaya"}, {"start": 25, "end": 31, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Gazeta"}, {"start": 56, "end": 70, "label": -1, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Chechen Muslim"}, {"start": 151, "end": 159, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Chechnya"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the russian news agency novaya gazeta has said it is \"retribution\" against russian men detained in chechnya.", "summary_upper": "The Russian news agency Novaya Gazeta has said it is `` retribution '' against Russian men detained in Chechnya .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 11, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 24, "end": 37, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Novaya Gazeta"}, {"start": 79, "end": 86, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 103, "end": 111, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Chechnya"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "russia's state tv agency has warned that a report by russia's state-run chechen leader chechen chechnya will be investigated by", "summary_upper": "Russia 's state TV agency has warned that a report by Russia 's state-run Chechen leader Chechen Chechnya will be investigated by", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 6, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 54, "end": 60, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Russia"}, {"start": 74, "end": 81, "label": 2, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Chechen"}, {"start": 89, "end": 96, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Chechen"}, {"start": 97, "end": 105, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Chechnya"}]}}, "34743526": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a private agency set up by a private agent to rent homes has been paid more than £1m in rent, documents obtained by the bbc reveal.", "summary_upper": "A private agency set up by a private agent to rent homes has been paid more than £1m in rent , documents obtained by the BBC reveal .", "ents": [{"start": 71, "end": 83, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "more than £1"}, {"start": 121, "end": 124, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "BBC"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "more than # 1m has been spent on private landlords in london for more than a decade, according to a report.", "summary_upper": "More than # 1M has been spent on private landlords in London for more than a decade , according to a report .", "ents": [{"start": 54, "end": 60, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "London"}, {"start": 65, "end": 83, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "more than a decade"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a letting agency has been paid more than # 5.5 m in housing benefit after its owner set up a charity to help the homeless, the bbc has learned.", "summary_upper": "A letting agency has been paid more than # 5.5 m in housing benefit after its owner set up a charity to help the homeless , the BBC has learned .", "ents": [{"start": 31, "end": 46, "label": -1, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "more than # 5.5"}, {"start": 128, "end": 131, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "BBC"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "homeless people in london are being asked to pay more than # [UNK] per month for homeless people in the uk, documents obtained by the bbc suggest.", "summary_upper": "Homeless people in London are being asked to pay more than # [ UNK ] per month for homeless people in the UK , documents obtained by the BBC suggest .", "ents": [{"start": 19, "end": 25, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "London"}, {"start": 49, "end": 62, "label": 1, "type": "MONEY", "ent": "more than # ["}, {"start": 63, "end": 66, "label": 1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UNK"}, {"start": 73, "end": 78, "label": 1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "month"}, {"start": 106, "end": 108, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}, {"start": 137, "end": 140, "label": 1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "BBC"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a scheme that helps homeless people living in the uk has been launched by private landlords.", "summary_upper": "A scheme that helps homeless people living in the UK has been launched by private landlords .", "ents": [{"start": 50, "end": 52, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}]}}, "37207414": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "great britain's men lost their opening eurobasket finals warm-up warm-up match against the netherlands in amsterdam.", "summary_upper": "Great Britain 's men lost their opening EuroBasket finals warm-up warm-up match against the Netherlands in Amsterdam .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 16, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Great Britain 's"}, {"start": 40, "end": 50, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "EuroBasket"}, {"start": 92, "end": 103, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Netherlands"}, {"start": 107, "end": 116, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Amsterdam"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "great britain women's hopes of qualifying for the eurobasket finals suffered a setback as they were beaten 2-1 by croatia.", "summary_upper": "Great Britain women 's hopes of qualifying for the EuroBasket finals suffered a setback as they were beaten 2-1 by Croatia .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 13, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Great Britain"}, {"start": 51, "end": 61, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "EuroBasket"}, {"start": 108, "end": 109, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "2"}, {"start": 115, "end": 122, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Croatia"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "great britain lost to the netherlands in manchester for the second time in two days, going down 79-68.", "summary_upper": "Great Britain lost to the Netherlands in Manchester for the second time in two days , going down 79-68 .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 13, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Great Britain"}, {"start": 26, "end": 37, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Netherlands"}, {"start": 41, "end": 51, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Manchester"}, {"start": 60, "end": 66, "label": -1, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "second"}, {"start": 75, "end": 83, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "two days"}, {"start": 97, "end": 99, "label": -1, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "79"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "great britain's hopes of qualifying for the eurobasket 2017 qualifier against great britain remain at the top of the eurobasket qualifying campaign.", "summary_upper": "Great Britain 's hopes of qualifying for the EuroBasket 2017 qualifier against Great Britain remain at the top of the EuroBasket qualifying campaign .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 16, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Great Britain 's"}, {"start": 79, "end": 92, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Great Britain"}, {"start": 118, "end": 128, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "EuroBasket"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "great britain's hopes of qualifying for the eurobasket finals suffered a setback with a 2-0 victory over hungary in the first round of qualifying", "summary_upper": "Great Britain 's hopes of qualifying for the EuroBasket finals suffered a setback with a 2-0 victory over Hungary in the first round of qualifying", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 16, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Great Britain 's"}, {"start": 45, "end": 55, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "EuroBasket"}, {"start": 89, "end": 90, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "2"}, {"start": 106, "end": 113, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Hungary"}, {"start": 121, "end": 126, "label": 0, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "first"}]}}, "38334966": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "how much do you remember about the news in wales over the past 12 months?", "summary_upper": "How much do you remember about the news in Wales over the past 12 months ?", "ents": [{"start": 43, "end": 48, "label": 1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Wales"}, {"start": 54, "end": 72, "label": 1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the past 12 months"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "all pictures are copyrighted.", "summary_upper": "All pictures are copyrighted .", "ents": []}, "Gold": {"summary": "how much do you remember about the news in wales over the past 12 months?", "summary_upper": "How much do you remember about the news in Wales over the past 12 months ?", "ents": [{"start": 43, "end": 48, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Wales"}, {"start": 54, "end": 72, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the past 12 months"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "how much do you remember about the christmas news, you might think about your questions about the christmas weather?", "summary_upper": "How much do you remember about the Christmas news , you might think about your questions about the Christmas weather ?", "ents": [{"start": 35, "end": 44, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "Christmas"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "how much do you remember about the news in wales over the past 12 months?", "summary_upper": "How much do you remember about the news in Wales over the past 12 months ?", "ents": [{"start": 43, "end": 48, "label": 1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Wales"}, {"start": 54, "end": 72, "label": 1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the past 12 months"}]}}, "40883148": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "conor mcgregor's fight against ufc champion conor mcgregor in las vegas on 9 august will be discussed by the nevada authorities.", "summary_upper": "Conor McGregor 's fight against UFC champion Conor McGregor in Las Vegas on 9 August will be discussed by the Nevada authorities .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Conor"}, {"start": 6, "end": 14, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "McGregor"}, {"start": 15, "end": 17, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "'s"}, {"start": 32, "end": 35, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UFC"}, {"start": 45, "end": 50, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Conor"}, {"start": 51, "end": 59, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "McGregor"}, {"start": 63, "end": 72, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Las Vegas"}, {"start": 76, "end": 84, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "9 August"}, {"start": 110, "end": 116, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Nevada"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "floyd mayweather's bid to become the first ufc boxing champion to be held in las vegas is to be held in las vegas.", "summary_upper": "Floyd Mayweather 's bid to become the first UFC boxing champion to be held in Las Vegas is to be held in Las Vegas .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Floyd"}, {"start": 6, "end": 16, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Mayweather"}, {"start": 17, "end": 19, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "'s"}, {"start": 44, "end": 47, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UFC"}, {"start": 78, "end": 87, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Las Vegas"}, {"start": 105, "end": 114, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Las Vegas"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "floyd mayweather has formally requested to use 8oz gloves when he fights conor mcgregor in las vegas on 26 august.", "summary_upper": "Floyd Mayweather has formally requested to use 8oz gloves when he fights Conor McGregor in Las Vegas on 26 August .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Floyd"}, {"start": 6, "end": 16, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Mayweather"}, {"start": 47, "end": 48, "label": -1, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "8"}, {"start": 73, "end": 78, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Conor"}, {"start": 79, "end": 87, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "McGregor"}, {"start": 91, "end": 100, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Las Vegas"}, {"start": 104, "end": 113, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "26 August"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "ufc lightweight champion liam bennett has said he is \"coming sprinting at you with bricks\" after his ufc career was rejected.", "summary_upper": "Ufc lightweight champion Liam Bennett has said he is `` coming sprinting at you with bricks '' after his UFC career was rejected .", "ents": [{"start": 25, "end": 29, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Liam"}, {"start": 30, "end": 37, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Bennett"}, {"start": 105, "end": 108, "label": 2, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UFC"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "ufc featherweight champion conor mcgregor will not be able to defend his ufc lightweight title against nate diaz, according to a leaked document.", "summary_upper": "Ufc featherweight champion Conor McGregor will not be able to defend his UFC lightweight title against Nate Diaz , according to a leaked document .", "ents": [{"start": 27, "end": 32, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Conor"}, {"start": 33, "end": 41, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "McGregor"}, {"start": 73, "end": 76, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UFC"}, {"start": 103, "end": 112, "label": 0, "type": "WORK_OF_ART", "ent": "Nate Diaz"}]}}, "36882573": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "two of the uk's longest-serving journalists are celebrating 100 years on the streets of fleet street.", "summary_upper": "Two of the UK 's longest-serving journalists are celebrating 100 years on the streets of Fleet street .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 3, "label": 2, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "Two"}, {"start": 11, "end": 13, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}, {"start": 61, "end": 70, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "100 years"}, {"start": 89, "end": 101, "label": 2, "type": "FAC", "ent": "Fleet street"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "all photographs by steve smith.", "summary_upper": "All photographs by Steve Smith .", "ents": [{"start": 19, "end": 24, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Steve"}, {"start": 25, "end": 30, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Smith"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "the last two journalists working in fleet street are leaving what was once seen as the centre of uk journalism.", "summary_upper": "The last two journalists working in fleet street are leaving what was once seen as the centre of UK journalism .", "ents": [{"start": 9, "end": 12, "label": -1, "type": "CARDINAL", "ent": "two"}, {"start": 97, "end": 99, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "the death of a journalist in london has been described as the \"street of shame\" as a journalist.", "summary_upper": "The death of a journalist in London has been described as the `` street of shame '' as a journalist .", "ents": [{"start": 29, "end": 35, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "London"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "journalists and journalists are celebrating the life of the city's most famous journalist.", "summary_upper": "Journalists and journalists are celebrating the life of the city 's most famous journalist .", "ents": []}}, "32680434": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "author jk rowling has said she has been blocked from posting abusive messages on twitter.", "summary_upper": "Author JK Rowling has said she has been blocked from posting abusive messages on Twitter .", "ents": [{"start": 81, "end": 88, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Twitter"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the author of jk rowling has said she has been \"shocked\" by comments she made about twitter about the scottish independence referendum.", "summary_upper": "The author of JK Rowling has said she has been `` shocked '' by comments she made about Twitter about the Scottish independence referendum .", "ents": [{"start": 14, "end": 24, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "JK Rowling"}, {"start": 106, "end": 114, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Scottish"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "jk rowling has thanked twitter users who offered words of support after she became a target for online abuse in the wake of the general election result.", "summary_upper": "Jk Rowling has thanked Twitter users who offered words of support after she became a target for online abuse in the wake of the general election result .", "ents": []}, "PtGen": {"summary": "harry potter author jk rowling has said she is \"no responsibility\" to protect the image of her books.", "summary_upper": "Harry Potter author JK Rowling has said she is `` no responsibility '' to protect the image of her books .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 5, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Harry"}, {"start": 6, "end": 12, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Potter"}, {"start": 20, "end": 22, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "JK"}, {"start": 23, "end": 30, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Rowling"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "the snp has hit back at twitter after tweeting that she's not doing enough to protect her from abusive behaviour.", "summary_upper": "The SNP has hit back at Twitter after tweeting that she 's not doing enough to protect her from abusive behaviour .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 7, "label": 1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "SNP"}, {"start": 24, "end": 31, "label": 1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Twitter"}]}}, "34802406": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "young people in scotland are more likely than their peers to commit violent crimes, according to new research.", "summary_upper": "Young people in Scotland are more likely than their peers to commit violent crimes , according to new research .", "ents": [{"start": 16, "end": 24, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "young girls in scotland are more likely to be linked to violent crime, according to a new study.", "summary_upper": "Young girls in Scotland are more likely to be linked to violent crime , according to a new study .", "ents": [{"start": 15, "end": 23, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "scotland's criminal justice system punishes poorer people and makes it difficult for them to escape poverty, according to an academic study.", "summary_upper": "Scotland 's criminal justice system punishes poorer people and makes it difficult for them to escape poverty , according to an academic study .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 8, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Scotland"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "young people who lived in extreme poverty are more likely to be placed on statutory supervision, a study suggests.", "summary_upper": "Young people who lived in extreme poverty are more likely to be placed on statutory supervision , a study suggests .", "ents": []}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "young people in edinburgh are more likely to be living in violent crime than girls, according to new research.", "summary_upper": "Young people in Edinburgh are more likely to be living in violent crime than girls , according to new research .", "ents": [{"start": 16, "end": 25, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Edinburgh"}]}}, "40866012": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a 25-year-old man has appeared in court charged with the murder of karl haugh, who was stabbed to death in county limerick in the", "summary_upper": "A 25-year-old man has appeared in court charged with the murder of Karl Haugh , who was stabbed to death in county Limerick in the", "ents": [{"start": 67, "end": 71, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Karl"}, {"start": 72, "end": 77, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Haugh"}, {"start": 115, "end": 123, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Limerick"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a man has appeared in court charged with the murder of mr walsh in the republic of ireland.", "summary_upper": "A man has appeared in court charged with the murder of Mr Walsh in the republic of Ireland .", "ents": [{"start": 55, "end": 57, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Mr"}, {"start": 58, "end": 63, "label": 2, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Walsh"}, {"start": 83, "end": 90, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Ireland"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a 21-year-old man has appeared in court in county clare charged over the fatal stabbing of karl haugh in kilkee at the weekend.", "summary_upper": "A 21-year-old man has appeared in court in county Clare charged over the fatal stabbing of Karl Haugh in Kilkee at the weekend .", "ents": [{"start": 50, "end": 55, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Clare"}, {"start": 91, "end": 95, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Karl"}, {"start": 96, "end": 101, "label": -1, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Haugh"}, {"start": 105, "end": 111, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Kilkee"}, {"start": 115, "end": 126, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "the weekend"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a man has appeared in court charged with the murder of a man outside a university in glasgow city centre.", "summary_upper": "A man has appeared in court charged with the murder of a man outside a university in Glasgow city centre .", "ents": [{"start": 85, "end": 97, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Glasgow city"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a man has appeared in court charged with the murder of a father-of-two in county limerick in august.", "summary_upper": "A man has appeared in court charged with the murder of a Father-Of-Two in county Limerick in August .", "ents": [{"start": 81, "end": 89, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Limerick"}, {"start": 93, "end": 99, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "August"}]}}, "35266927": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a sinn fein mla is to pay compensation to a member of the ulster defence association ( udr ) over a tweet he made about a former", "summary_upper": "A Sinn Fein MLA is to pay compensation to a member of the Ulster defence Association ( UDR ) over a Tweet he made about a former", "ents": [{"start": 54, "end": 84, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "the Ulster defence Association"}, {"start": 87, "end": 90, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UDR"}, {"start": 100, "end": 105, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Tweet"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "sinn féin mla tom elliott has been told by a high court judge that he is \"deeply sorry\" by the high court in belfast.", "summary_upper": "Sinn Féin MLA Tom Elliott has been told by a high court judge that he is `` deeply sorry '' by the high court in Belfast .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 4, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Sinn"}, {"start": 5, "end": 9, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Féin"}, {"start": 14, "end": 17, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tom"}, {"start": 18, "end": 25, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Elliott"}, {"start": 113, "end": 120, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Belfast"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a sinn féin mla has agreed to apologise and pay compensation to a former ulster unionist leader over a defamatory message posted on twitter.", "summary_upper": "A Sinn Féin MLA has agreed to apologise and pay compensation to a former Ulster Unionist leader over a defamatory message posted on Twitter .", "ents": [{"start": 73, "end": 88, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Ulster Unionist"}, {"start": 132, "end": 139, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Twitter"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "sinn féin mla tom elliott has apologised for a tweet about a member of the udr \"udr\" .", "summary_upper": "Sinn Féin MLA Tom Elliott has apologised for a tweet about a member of the UDR `` UDR '' .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 4, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Sinn"}, {"start": 5, "end": 9, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Féin"}, {"start": 14, "end": 17, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Tom"}, {"start": 18, "end": 25, "label": 0, "type": "PERSON", "ent": "Elliott"}, {"start": 75, "end": 78, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UDR"}, {"start": 82, "end": 85, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "UDR"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a sinn fein mla has said he is  totally disrespectful \" over comments he made about a dup mla on twitter.\"", "summary_upper": "A Sinn Fein MLA has said he is totally disrespectful `` over comments he made about a DUP MLA on Twitter . ''", "ents": [{"start": 2, "end": 15, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Sinn Fein MLA"}, {"start": 97, "end": 104, "label": 0, "type": "LOC", "ent": "Twitter"}]}}, "13193011": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a borders knitwear firm has announced a new production range, following a rise in demand for its clothing.", "summary_upper": "A borders knitwear firm has announced a new production range , following a rise in demand for its clothing .", "ents": []}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "production firm production has announced it is to close its production in europe.", "summary_upper": "Production firm production has announced it is to close its production in Europe .", "ents": [{"start": 74, "end": 80, "label": 0, "type": "LOC", "ent": "Europe"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a borders textile firm has announced a 20% increase in its turnover, to Â # 8m a year, in its annual accounts.", "summary_upper": "A borders textile firm has announced a 20 % increase in its turnover , to Â # 8M a year , in its annual accounts .", "ents": [{"start": 39, "end": 43, "label": -1, "type": "PERCENT", "ent": "20 %"}, {"start": 97, "end": 103, "label": -1, "type": "DATE", "ent": "annual"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a knitwear knitwear firm has been bought by a private equity firm in a bid to save its production of garments.", "summary_upper": "A knitwear knitwear firm has been bought by a private equity firm in a bid to save its production of garments .", "ents": []}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "knitwear brand hawick knitwear has made its new full-year profit for the first time in more than two years.", "summary_upper": "Knitwear brand Hawick knitwear has made its new full-year profit for the first time in more than two years .", "ents": [{"start": 15, "end": 21, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Hawick"}, {"start": 48, "end": 57, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "full-year"}, {"start": 73, "end": 78, "label": 2, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "first"}, {"start": 87, "end": 106, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "more than two years"}]}}, "35051818": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "a lollipop lady was hit on the head by a lollipop lady as he walked her home from school, a court has heard.", "summary_upper": "A Lollipop lady was hit on the head by a lollipop lady as he walked her home from school , a court has heard .", "ents": [{"start": 2, "end": 10, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Lollipop"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "a man accused of causing the death of a six-year-old girl in a car crash has been jailed for six years.", "summary_upper": "A man accused of causing the death of a six-year-old girl in a car crash has been jailed for six years .", "ents": [{"start": 40, "end": 52, "label": 0, "type": "DATE", "ent": "six-year-old"}, {"start": 93, "end": 102, "label": 2, "type": "DATE", "ent": "six years"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "a driver who knocked down a lollipop lady broke down in tears in court as he said he was \"truly sorry\" for her and her family.", "summary_upper": "A driver who knocked down a lollipop lady broke down in tears in court as he said he was `` truly sorry '' for her and her family .", "ents": []}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a lollipop lady has been blinded in a world upside down\" after admitting causing the death of a lollipop lady", "summary_upper": "A Lollipop lady has been blinded in a world upside down '' after admitting causing the death of a lollipop lady", "ents": [{"start": 2, "end": 10, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Lollipop"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summary": "a man accused of causing a pensioner's death by careless driving has told a court he was  truly sorry \" he had been \".\"", "summary_upper": "A man accused of causing a pensioner 's death by careless driving has told a court he was truly sorry `` he had been `` . ''", "ents": []}}, "32715299": {"BERTS2S": {"summary": "the uk's navy and nato warships have begun a major exercise in the waters off britain's west coast.", "summary_upper": "The UK 's Navy and NATO warships have begun a major exercise in the waters off Britain 's West Coast .", "ents": [{"start": 4, "end": 6, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}, {"start": 10, "end": 14, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "Navy"}, {"start": 19, "end": 23, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "NATO"}, {"start": 79, "end": 86, "label": 2, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Britain"}, {"start": 90, "end": 100, "label": 2, "type": "LOC", "ent": "West Coast"}]}, "TConvS2S": {"summary": "the royal navy's most powerful naval ship, it, is on the verge of becoming the first naval vessel to be conducted in the uk.", "summary_upper": "The Royal Navy 's most powerful naval ship , it , is on the verge of becoming the first Naval vessel to be conducted in the UK .", "ents": [{"start": 0, "end": 17, "label": 0, "type": "ORG", "ent": "The Royal Navy 's"}, {"start": 82, "end": 87, "label": 0, "type": "ORDINAL", "ent": "first"}, {"start": 124, "end": 126, "label": 0, "type": "GPE", "ent": "UK"}]}, "Gold": {"summary": "in the north sea, off the coast of norway, nato has been conducting its largest ever anti-submarine warfare exercise.", "summary_upper": "In the North Sea , off the coast of Norway , NATO has been conducting its largest ever anti-submarine warfare exercise .", "ents": [{"start": 3, "end": 16, "label": -1, "type": "LOC", "ent": "the North Sea"}, {"start": 36, "end": 42, "label": -1, "type": "GPE", "ent": "Norway"}, {"start": 45, "end": 49, "label": -1, "type": "ORG", "ent": "NATO"}]}, "PtGen": {"summary": "a russian u-boat in the bowels of the surface of the surface ship has been spotted in the sky for a few hours.", "summary_upper": "A Russian U-Boat in the bowels of the surface of the surface ship has been spotted in the sky for a few hours .", "ents": [{"start": 2, "end": 9, "label": 0, "type": "NORP", "ent": "Russian"}, {"start": 98, "end": 109, "label": 2, "type": "TIME", "ent": "a few hours"}]}, "TranS2S": {"summ